二零二二年安徽省初中学业水平考试。
Anhui Province. B, and C.
一短对话理解，你将听到五段对话，每段对话后。
哦，有一个小题，请在每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
Well, helping patients makes me feel happy.
Why did you choose to be a doctor, not a policeman or an engineer?
you take the picture in Sunshine Park?
Yes, we went camping there.
Jenny played the guitar and we had fun.
Did you take the picture in Sunshine Park?
Yes, we went camping there.
Jenny played the guitar and we had fun.
3. Will you spend the mid -autumn day with your family or friends?
Neither. It is also Teacher's Day this year, so I'll spend it with my teachers.
4. Helen, have you called to tell Jim about our travel plan?
No, but I sent him an email and have got his text message.
He will join us.
5. me the trip?
but I sent him an email and have got his text message.
He will join us.
5. me, would you please bring me the soup?
Usually, we serve the main course first, but we'll bring you the soup first if you
like, sir. me, would you please bring me the soup?
like, sir. Hi, Jenny.
听下面一段对话，回答第六七题。
You've got a new book, haven't you?
Yes, Bob. It's a birthday gift from my history teacher.
It's about ancient China.
It's interesting. prefer to read books about famous people like Qian Xue Sen and Tu
You You. I want to be a scientist like them in the future.
You're joking, aren't you?
You never liked science before.
Ha I've started to like it.
Hi, Jenny. You've got a new book, haven't you?
Yes, Bob. It's a birthday gift from my history teacher.
It's about ancient China.
It's interesting. I prefer to read books about famous people like Qian Xue Sen and
Tu You You.
I want to be a scientist like them in the future.
You're joking, aren't you?
You never liked science before.
Ha ha. I've started to like it.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十题。
You're with your new living environment, right?
Certainly. The new community was built last year, and my house is near a lake with
green trees around it.
I can hear birds sing and smell flowers every day.
Lovely. Then is it near your office?
No, but the community is simply perfect.
I also find the neighbors are willing to help one another.
How lucky you are!
I hear you moved to a new house last month, Daniel.
Just last week.
You know, my old house is next to a factory.
It's noisy sometimes.
So you are pleased with your new living environment, right?
Certainly. The new community was built last year, and my house is near a lake with
green trees around it.
I can hear birds sing and smell flowers every day.
Lovely. Then is it near your office?
No, but the community is simply perfect.
I also find the neighbors are willing to help one another.
How lucky you are!
三短文理解。
你将听到一篇短文，短文后有五个小题，请根据短文内容，在每小题所给
Please read the short text twice.
三个选项中选出。
Our girls football team tried very hard during the first two months this year.
Nancy moved very quickly in the football field, and Betty passed the ball very well.
However, Amy, leader of the team, didn't feel very well on the day of the
quarterfinal match.
Although they all tried their best, they lost the match.
What a pity!
The boys football team did better.
With Tom leading them, they got into the final for the first time.
But the match was difficult for the boys because of the poor weather condition.
Our school team seldom practiced in such wet weather before.
At the very end, Tom scored a goal and our team won the final.
Congratulations to all our football players!
The whole school are proud of you!
What a great season for sports at our school!
The three -month football games began in March.
All the players played well.
Our girls football team tried very hard during the first two months this year.
Nancy moved very quickly in the football field, and Betty passed the ball very well.
However, Amy, leader of the team, didn't feel very well on the day of the
quarterfinal match. Although they all tried their best, they lost the match.
What a pity!
The boys football team did better.
With Tom leading them, they got into the final for the first time.
But the match was difficult for the boys because of the poor weather condition.
Our school team seldom practiced in such wet weather before.
At the very end, Tom scored a goal and our team won the final.
Congratulations to all our football players!
The whole school are proud of you!
四信息转换。
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容写出下面表格中所缺的单词，每空仅
填一词。
短文读两遍。
When you have something to say, you should take time to think before you speak.
Don't just say it right away.
You need to make sure your words are true.
Never share wrong information.
You should also try your best to be kind and not to hurt others.
What's more, say what is necessary, and you won't make problems for yourself.
When communicating, think about other people's feelings.
It's also important not to use bad words, for nobody likes hearing them.
If you don't like your words, then keep quiet.
Remember, once you say something, you can't take it back.
When you have something to say, you should take time to think before you speak.
Don't just say it right away.
You need to make sure your words are true.
Never share wrong information.
You should also try your best to be kind and not to hurt others.
What's more, say what is necessary, and you won't make problems for yourself.
When communicating, think about other people's feelings.
It's also important not to use bad words, for nobody likes hearing them.
If you don't like your words, then keep quiet.
Remember, once you say something, you can't take it back.
听力测试结束，请关注“锦鲤英语”微信公众号
If you like words,